uh friends from irm during my time
he's also here uh so thanks atul for
referring me to karchanim so that we
could host this
talk series today and also know i'll
thank
my friends who is
two years senior to me and my bachmann
priest raj who's also here in this
session for their encouragement
so students good afternoon i hope uh
you guys are all uh you know uh eager to
understand more about insurance industry
today right
uh sir if i can take a permission from
you sir we have an anchor also would
like to introduce you to the other
audience as well
sure please go in success
isn't overnight it's when every day you
get a little better than before
it adds up a very good afternoon to
respected director fms irem
dr jesse john maam security director fms
irm
dr turjani ghulam a prestigious chief
speaker mr samrad ghosh
associate vice president sma digital at
icici lombard
all the talented faculty members and my
fellow mates
i sanvi gupta a pgdm student of fms irm
would like to extend my heartiest
welcome to you all
in the alumni talk series ron davos
fms irm is ranked a triple plus among
india's top day schools
and first among the best b schools of
rajasthan
fms irm has a proud legacy of advancing
the careers of students
and transforming organizations toward a
better tomorrow
it is indeed my great pleasure to
welcome among
us the alumni of this institution
alumni talk series is a program done
under the alumni association
of sms irm in which we wholeheartedly
welcome
our reputed alumni to connect and share
the valuable views with us
it will be my pleasure to introduce an
eminent senior of mine
not only it is a movement of happiness
and nostalgia for us
but also an opportunity to reflect on
our learnings and achievements
a sales and marketing professional with
19 years of experience
had sme digital and avid yes
i'm talking about a guest of the day mr
mr samrad ghosh
in the present role at icici lombard
he's head
at sme digital where he manages a new
and only website presently in india
completely catering to sme segment
he has hosted numerous quizzes as a quiz
master across
india he is also a guest faculty in
digital marketing and insurance
management
at misb buccaneer management institute
mumbai
nitdi mumbai don bosco institute of
management guwahati
department of management studies assam
university
now i would like to invite respected
deputy director sms
irm dr tarjani goyal mom for official
welcome
of our chief guest thank you so much
tanvi
thank you mama i am perfectly audible
yes ma'am very good afternoon to
everyone
and especially i must say i must
initiate with a
by saying thanks to you sir for
accepting our uh invitation
i hardly welcome our guest guest of the
day mr sambar ghost
on behalf of a famous hiring to this
prestigious moment
when actually we have uh an an
aluminist who has reached the helm of
the affairs of the company and in spite
of his busy schedule
he is been managing things during this
covert times
he didn't hesitate and has taken up uh
and instantly agreed upon
to after looking at the program where
his alma mater is calling him
basically this platform gives the young
managers
a time where they can celebrate the
achievement of their own
eliminates he can refresh upon his old
memories certainly with his friends here
if they are here as well with him and we
also give a platform to the students to
create new relationship with these kinds
of alumni
we'll look forward for an interactive
session with you and students sir
i welcome once again you to your own
home
to your own place and we would look
forward
for your visit when the things get ease
out once again welcome you sir
thank you so much
[Music]
over to you thank you so much mom
now i would like to request our chief
guest
or to carry forward the session
okay thank you you for the lovely
introduction and thank you ma'am
for welcoming me uh as i uh
as i was saying initially that uh i'd
like to thank
katul jerial my immediate junior at irm
who has been a lot of close friends
since last 20 years for
referring me uh for this talk series
and i also thank uh mr ashton who has
been two years senior to me
at irm and priya my
for encouraging me and these two people
are there i guess
in this uh zoom call now
so good afternoon students uh
i hope you all are eager to know more
about insurance industry and the
opportunities uh you know as a insurance
as an opportunity a career opportunity
for you
all so i will talk i want to
talk in details about insurance industry
i will try to give you some
just some brief snippets about insurance
industry
how it has evolved over the years
and what are the trends which is there
in the insurance industry at present
the size of the market to understand the
opportunities insurance and
how digital has played a role
in what insurance industries today so
i'll start off with the presentation so
if somebody can help me out you know
display the presentation
it will be great
it's a little visible yes sir
good afternoon good afternoon sir i am
there with you
okay thank you so much uh for helping me
out with the presentation
hello sir okay uh
so uh insurance is as old as
5000 years you know if you study uh
insurance history uh insurance started
during alexander's time
so the concept of insurance the modern
insurance started
in in around 13
14th century lloyd's in england so
lloyd's in england is very famous for
insurance and lloyd is
one of the oldest insurance company
present uh today
so i won't talk much about you know the
great
history of insurance but what i will
talk about is about the
immediate uh history of insurance sector
in india
sorry if you can just uh put in the next
slide the first line
yeah so as you know insurance industry
is regulated
uh so ird is the regulator for the
insurance industry and irda was set up
uh
in 1999. and in 2000
april 2000 iid act was promulgated in
the parliament
and came into being and uh post uh
you know privatization of insurance
industry in 2000
uh before that there were only one life
insurance company that is
you know lici or life insurance
corporation of india
and we are around four general insurance
company you know
which is uh oriental insurance company
new india insurance company general
insurance company and
these are new indian insurance insurance
companies which we have so
this was all it till 2000 post april
2000 when
you know irda was set up so insurance
industry was opened up
it was privatized and we saw you know so
many insurance companies coming
uh and applying for license uh
now i'll tell you about how many number
of insurance companies we have in the
country right now
uh in our next life but before that uh
i'll also try to tell you about
what has happened in uh you know last 20
years in insurance
now as you know insurance was primarily
uh
sold through a distribution model which
is agency distribution models
where you know individual people can
become an agent
as per certain guidelines prescribed by
insurance companies
if they you know fall under that
guidance they
they are accepted as agents you know to
sell insurance
now when irda came into being they
started a new process
of licensing agents so that agents
uh you know who sell insurance are given
licensed by iidm
who sell insurance provided they pass
their exam there is a
simple exam which takes place conducted
by insurance institute of india
so the after that we
saw a private insurance company coming
in
and breaking the monopoly of lic and
other general insurance company
distribution was
you know challenging for them uh in the
agency model so
they started uh focusing uh tie-ups with
banks which is also known as bank
assurance model of distribution now if
you look at the immediate history of
bank assurance bank assurance
distribution started uh first time it
was there with the bnp paribas it's a
you know french based bank and they had
an insurance company called cardiff
insurance so cardiff tied up with the
branches of
bnp paris across
france and started distributing
insurance to bank branches so that's the
start of bank assurance
in you know early 70s uh in
in the european market that's how indian
insurance
private insurers also started uh taking
a few out of
uh you know cardiff's book and started
tying up with various banks across the
country
and if you look at most of the insurance
companies which applied for license and
what uh
insurance companies license are
primarily uh you know
uh no banks so bait icici or sdfc or
kota
so these are all primarily big banks or
big uh business conglomerates like
adulterer group or tata group
uh you know to name a few so
uh you know one of the important trends
which you saw in insurance in
rd2000 or b2000 the emergence of
bank assurance as a distribution channel
and
we also saw uh you know certain uh you
know
market changes uh we had global turmoil
in 2008 2009 after which we saw
you know the product distribution
insurance started uh
you know taking the change in the
distribution uh
started taking place we saw companies
focusing on digitization or
started uh you know selling to the
digital uh
medium or not or or you know
onboarding customer in a uh not in a
traditional
uh format but in our digital format
that's how
the initial digitization started uh
these are the basic
trends or the few you know immediate
history of insurance in
last 20 years and coming to the next
slide which talks about you know early
trends in digitization
now we have seen uh there has been a
digital transformation in the insurance
industry
but how this transformation took place
right today you can buy
you know insurance on the go in a
seamless manner
in various insurance companies website
or or various
distribution companies like policy
bazaars of the world they are
they are not insurance companies but
they are distribution
or as you call agents of insurance
company so they are called web
aggregators
technical terminology which they use is
web aggregators where they show
you know the pricing of various
insurance company of features of various
insurance company bases your likings you
choose and pick any insurance company
and buy it from the platform
so this was not so this journey of
policy bazaar
or various insurance companies who sell
insurance but not so easy
the knowledge was limited uh in terms of
digital uh
you know transformation uh and how you
know
you have to make it uh customer savvy or
how how you want to make it more uh you
know
seamless in uh giving customers a better
experience
insurance company didn't have any idea
because they are not debt companies they
are basically insurance companies they
understand how to
write insurance products or underwrite
an insurance product
and sell it so insurance is nothing but
a risk or taking the risk of that person
or that
object for which it is getting insured
so it's more about risk management
so they didn't have much of an idea of
how to bring in a seamlessness how to
bring in customer
better you know user interface or better
experience in their website
what they did initially was uh
converting a normal physical formula
digital form that was the
start or the initial currency
digitization so
companies thought let us convert the
physical form of eight nine pages
because life insurance or general
insurance
uh insurance uh policy forms
or for enrolling customers were very
tedious it was long where you have to
fill up a lot of pages
of information plus you have to give lot
of documents
to identify yourself as per kyc
and then your policy is to get it uh you
know issue
so the insurance company initially
started uh
you know focusing on uh you know digital
for
you know getting the physical function
to digital format
then came uh you know certain
transformation in india's
overall uh you know uh economy and
indian market where he saw
emergence of a lot of uh
e-commerce players flipkart started in
2007.
amazon came in 2013 uh snapdeal started
around 2008 nine
rounds and a lot of other insurance
comes a lot of other e-commerce company
also came in
so this company bought a lot of uh you
know
behavioral changes in the indian
market plus they also
brought in lot of technological uh
changes
in the online buying process plus they
have bought in exemplary customer
service
plus you know seamless uh
you know customer experience and user
interface uh
in their apps so insurance company took
a leap out of that
and they also tried to uh you know
do something uh in their website
and in their uh you know
buying journey to bring in a lot of you
know seamlessness by
changing uh you know the user interface
the customer journeys
and converting the digital form which
was
you know too long into simple things so
that was the initial trends
which took place in the digital in the
digital uh transformation
uh in the insurance industry then if you
look at the market size
of insurance so presently it's roughly
around
180 billion dollars uh sir if you go to
the next slide
uh so 180 billion dollars is the roughly
uh
the insurance market size is on 2020
uh it's a big dated figure which i'm
putting now
and as on march 31st 2021 there are 57
uh insurance companies across life
insurance general insurance and health
insurance put together
so out of which there are 24
life insurance company and 33 general
insurance or
non-life insurance companies and
and digital or the digital business
insurance constitutes roughly around two
percent of the
overall insurance market that's how the
size of the insurance industry is all
about
now if you convert it to indian rupees
so roughly around
three um it will be around three lakh
fifteen
that's the size of the insurance
industry as per
indian rupees so there's a huge
opportunity and
insurance constitute just 3.5 percent
of the gdp when insurance
was privatized before that before 2000
the insurance penetration or
contribution to towards the gdp of the
country were
less than five percent point five
percent it has gone to three point five
percent to four percent now and
insurance penetration including all the
government initiative
expect around 15 but uh realistically
uh if you look at individual policies it
should not be more than
six to six point seven or seven percent
so that's the penetration level of
insurance so there is a huge
opportunity for insurance in india so
coming to the next slide which talks
about the opportunities of insurance in
online space
which our discussion today is about
knowing uh insurance industry and how
insurance industry
can be the potential of insurance
industry can be tapped uh
in the online space so as you know uh
you know there has been a general shift
of the you know indian working class
and uh we are one of the youngest
working population across the across the
globe
and the tg which we uh
have uh working population pga is around
25 to 35
uh years old and that constitutes around
60 percent of the overall working
population of our country
so there's a huge uh potential
uh you know of insurance because uh
young people
are driving a lot of uh insurance demand
in the
online space because they are used to
buying things
online plus uh their focus is on no
friends uh
insurance policy because of which we see
a trend uh
in uh life insurance especially buying a
lot of uh
you know term insurance or plane vanilla
insurance which is
uh and which is called the autumn
insurance
we saw millions focusing on those
products and
since last five years we have seen how
the market has changed
from an uh traditional or any only
product to
you know focusing on
true uh you know plain vanilla life
cover which is term insurance
because uh you know youngsters prefer
you know
less advice they want to understand
product
in their own terms which is explained in
the you know company's website or any
platform and they buy it
simply so because of which uh you know
this behavior a lot of
demand is getting created for the
insurance in the online space
now if you look at the present pandemic
which is there since last
one one year so this has also
driven uh you know distribution of
insurance in the online space
even the physical distributors like
banks or say agents also brokers
even they are not able to meet up class
clients to explain the product right
even they are also using digital medium
to reach out to the customers
either they are having their own
creating their own platforms or they are
seeking help from the insurance company
to give them a platform uh offer them a
platform so that they can
uh you know send it to their clients
explain the product
and sell insurance plus uh
now the young tg or the pg is a
term which we use uh in the marketing
for a target audience
uh so the this tg is uh you know digital
safety hence
they are driving digital distribution so
those are the you know basic reasons
because of which uh there is a huge
opportunity
for insurance in the online space
now if you go to the next slide so it
talks about
how to expand in the digital space now
an insurance company if they want to
digitalize or sell
insurance in the digital platform now
they wanted to
they also want to know how big is the
space
how big is the opportunity and how they
can expand
now in bank insurance model the more the
number of tie-ups you have with the bank
so more enhanced distribution you have
similar in agency model more the number
of agents you have more enhanced
distribution you have now here in
digital space
how you can uh you know increase your
digital distribution one is you know
getting your website
uh you know robust and responsive
website which
runs well uh or seamlessly both in
desktop and mobile and provide omni
channel service
which is offline and online service
board
so that you can service the client
now bringing those set of target
audience to your website or to your
mobile website is to reach out through
various
uh digital activities or digital
marketing and social media activities
right
so this is a traditional marketing or
traditional way of reaching out to the
customers
but uh or bringing the no customers in
the digital front now
how do you expand more other than your
website business
uh in the digital space that's where you
know the main challenge is
and if insurance company are able to
solve this puzzle
then insurance can be sold on the go
digitally in any of the transactions
so we see web of uh you know e-commerce
company and digital companies coming up
right you see startups
uh coming up in india you know every
year and
every year since last three years we
have seen startups
valuation going up billion they are
becoming unicorns
which means they are giving billion
dollar valuations
so this year already we have six uh
seven uh
insurance seven startups which has
already become unique
so uh now if this entire in a web
of uh digital companies uh wherein
you know people transact uh be it phone
pay or say flipkart or say amazon
or you know lens card or uh
so we'll see lot of startups in various
segments
in e-commerce segment in edutex segment
in food tech segment
in travel tech segment so you know all
our hours will be in the travel tech
segment
could be in the edutech segment you know
so uh you know
pay or you know phone pay are a part of
the fintech uh fintech segment so
it's a whole system of uh you know
network of ecosystem which is getting
created
and if insurance companies are able to
you know create partnership
opportunities or you know
expand uh the distribution uh through
this
uh mediums then the overall
you know distribution of digital
ecosystem will expand and this will help
insurance industry to expand in the
digital media
no so digitize you know existing
if we can you know change the or
digitize
the existing distribution channel like
bank assurance channel if i can
you know digitize the process
uh giving a customer a link
or an opportunity to buy insurance in
the
bank app itself because any banking
customer will have their bank app
mobile app they will be using if
insurance companies are present
in that bank app so customer can buy it
so this is basically digitizing the
existing distribution channel similarly
if an agent is given
a law you know a platform already can
share this platform to the customer to
explain the product and
wherein there is a you know payment
option of the customer
can do the payment and submit the
documents online so
this also serves the purpose of the
agent to sell uh you know
insurance in the digital medium and the
final option which the the insurance
companies
has is to create partnership
opportunities in the
digital ecosystem which was talking
about so these are the ways with
which you know insurance can be
you know expanded in the digital space
now this
also calls for a huge carrier
opportunity for all
youngsters uh or young managers who are
uh eager to join
the corporate world within the next
couple of months
i know because uh there is an
opportunity in various
segments uh now now if you look at the
carrier opportunity
which we have uh in the insurance
segment uh
you know it's wisdom sir if you'll go to
the next slide so you'll understand
this you know expansion of
insurance business in the digital space
is creating career opportunities for
professionals young professionals like
you in the insurance industry
and i will suggest and i will
always uh try to guide people in
insurance industry who wants to
make a career out of insurance because
uh i was one of the
few uh you know members of our badge who
started in children and still stay put
in charge since last 19 years
uh so insurance is a i've seen uh
you know huge uh level of growth in my
career
in insurance plus a huge opportunity
to learn uh from the industry stalwarts
as well as uh knowing a lot of people in
the financial service industry because
of my extended enjoyments
now if you look at the carrier
opportunity now earlier you know during
our time it was only into physical
distribution
either you become an agency manager like
uh you know
development officer of lic or a general
insurance company while you go and meet
people
try to make the major agents under you
and train them and
try to sell insurance to them so that
was the only
uh option for us
as a carrier in insurance when we joined
in 2003 2004
when insurance was uh you know
privatization of insurance or insurance
industries in this country
but now if we look at is more evolved
distribution channels has evolved
you know agency channel or tide agency
which is uh the prominent distribution
uh channel for insurance in india uh
as uh you know this has uh taken a
paradigm shift now bank assurance
is one of the primary and the most uh
important
for any insurance companies now if you
look at all private insurance companies
so bank assurance would be their
the strongest channel for uh most of the
private insurance companies
and bank assurance constitutes nearly 60
to 70 percent of overall business
and in certain companies it can be up to
80 percent
uh because uh agency business or agency
distribution is shrinking
now digital distribution is improving so
what are the opportunities uh in digital
insurance
was is into product management where in
how to bring in product
or what sort of product you want to
bring in uh you know
as a category manager or as a product
manager in your website
which will sell as well as you have to
track the performance of the product
which you have
made it live in your website it's
exactly like how a
product manager at flipkart or amazon
manages their products
for example flipkart i know brings a new
product for example a mobile phone
of a particular brand so product manager
of the mobile phone category will see
which brand of mobile phone is doing
good
or which model of mobile phone is doing
good or which
price segment is doing good basis that
you will try to quick uh
you know use uh you know economic uh
micro economic models as well as
you know marketing mix to you know
enhance uh customer experience and
entice a customer to purchase
now a moment you'll say for example few
of them would be like giving a discount
for no that's two hours or special days
or big billion days which you see in
amazon or great india shopping festival
which you
see in uh amazon it's a big billion days
at flipkart and
great india shopping festival which you
see in uh you know amazon these are the
few ways
to drive you know consumption and
the category managers of various product
categories
work in tandem with the overall
marketing team to drive
their category similarly you also have
an option
in insurance to drive your product
category
you know in the online space so
in life insurance there are various
category of products in general
insurance there are various categories
of products
uh you know in life insurance to name a
few
few categories would be a traditional
product i know
you live product or unit link products
or clean term insurance or child plants
so or retirement plans so these are the
various category of production life
insurance
in general insurance category it will be
more it will be more related to
uh it will be more related to the
overall segment like motor insurance
segment travel insurance
you know health insurance or say home
insurance
these are the various uh segments or
various categories uh you know
on which you can work as a product
manager uh other
option in career and you know carriers
in insurance would be
you know managing the website and the
online sales
so if somebody who of you are technical
graduates who understand uh
you know how you know and website works
the technology behind the website
uh the coding part the javascripts and
the html part of website how it works
then you can also have a carrier in you
know managing the technical aspect of
the website
and driving online sales because if your
website is up and running if your
website has got a better
customer experience which you uh work on
and create this will uh enhance your
online sales this will
improve your uh you know revenue per
click
in your website and you should also
improve your
i know visit to code and go to
you know purchase final purchase i know
so this is a second segment wherein you
can make a carrier
out of insurance third is the
conventional or
the traditional marketing which is
digital marketing
uh if you have got understanding of
social media marketing or performance
marketing
or your idea of seo which is a bit of a
technical part uh
if you've got uh you know knowledge
regarding that or if you want
uh if you have a small uh you know
you can even do some small courses
online to have an idea of
seo and digital marketing so you can you
know
carve out a career out of you know
digital marketing in seo
plus the other option while going
digital is digital partnership and
strategic alliances
so you have an option of reaching out to
various companies uh with your products
portfolio and the bouquet of products
which
you have in the services which you offer
to your customers and create
a bundle solution for for customers of
that
company whom you are trying to you know
pitch in a distribution uh
partnership option for example uh you
know
try to flip card or tie up with amazon
or tie up with ola
you know so in my one of my previous
companies i tied up with flipkart to
sell
i know uh insurance for tv
and refrigerators and mobile phones so
when you buy
on the flipkart platform so
so that's a tie-up so for this you need
to understand the product
and you need to understand the you know
how a customer
in flipkart uh you know behaves
and you could understand the customer
psychology the behavior
why is buying the product uh you know
online and basis that
stitch a plan or create a solution
around that
process to bundle insurance while buying
a phone or a mobile phone a phone or a
color television or you know
color television or you know any other
electronic products on the platform plus
uh you can also
you know do a lot of triumphs in the you
know
travel travel tech category like partner
with oio to sell
certain insurance solution partner with
make my trip to sell
travel solutions uh partner with ola
rover to provide excellent insurance
solutions so there are various
opportunities
which will have in partnership so
digital partnership and
strategic alliances is one of the key
distribution these days
since last four five years and i've
worked in this uh
you know strategic partnership role also
in my previous company so
it's a huge opportunity opportunity to
meet a lot of people
understand various insurance uh various
industry how
the in various industry works and how
you can
you know create solution for those
industry
you have to be very innovative and very
uh you know
go-getter to reach out to those
companies with your solution
plus uh you also have a career
opportunity in your traditional
distribution
channel which is a agency channel or a
bank assurance channel or a broker
and bring in your digital knowledge
to help the traditional channel digitize
or improve their digital footprint or
digital distribution to reach out to
more
customers so these are one of few career
opportunities
which you have in insurance but uh
before you
all i know you know take a plunge in
insurance industry as a career
i would also like to inform you that
this insurance industry is very
uh you know tough i won't say
it's an easy cakewalk it will be an easy
takeoff for everybody
uh because uh it has got
tremendous uh opportunity as well as it
has got tremendous pressure
you know you have to understand that so
i request all of you
to you know learn
more about insurance industry before you
take your plunge
to make a carrier routine insurance to
know what are your strengths
work on your strengths uh i was uh i was
not a technical guy
but i uh you know learned uh you know
technology uh how
you know website works how you know
website functions how a mobile app works
or
how a mobile website works how do you
design websites so that it is compatible
both
in uh you know desktop and in mobile so
i've learned over the years so
i'll request you to be a keen learner
because insurance industry is evolving
the distribution models are evolving the
technology is evolved
so what i learned five years back in
digital marketing
doesn't hold both today no in
2013 2014 i was doing a lot of affiliate
marketing i was doing
cost per lead this doesn't work these
days you know
now we have you know completely
different dimension to digital marketing
now the reach to the customer is
different we reach
you know earlier we used to do a you
know mass reach to the customer
these days we don't do mass reach we
personalize reach
so we personalize you know sending
customer centric
communication to each and every
potential customer so
digital marketing is also evolving so
keep abreast
of the latest technology uh you know
or the latest trends taking place in the
digital
digital industry digital marketing plus
overall
industry and i won't uh
you know talk much i
request you all the young students at
irm
who are eager to join the corporate uh
you know world within a couple of months
to ask uh questions uh i don't want to
make it just a monologue let it be a
two-way talk
i guess i have spoken enough uh in terms
of
uh insurance industries evolution in
last 20 years
the digitization which has taken place
plus the opportunities which you have
insurance
as a carrier now i make the house open
for
question and answer session and i'll be
glad to
answer all your queries so can somebody
help me
uh you know let me know what are the
questions which
the question students might
you is really very interesting your
enriching experience so uh before i
proceed with my students i would i would
like to ask one question if you allow me
actually the entire thing that even i'm
taking care of marketing subjects here
and probably digitization or
digitalization is one of the immense
component that we
can think of it's been an integral uh
element every now and then
but as far as insurance industry is
concerned some
as you said that after 2010 the trend
hasn't taken up the momentum
so uh my inquisitiveness is regarding
when things happen uh moreover the
hundred percent revolve around this
digitalization then what are the
challenges
that basically the company specifically
to the insurance have faced
initially what according to you can be
uh the constraints what according to you
what the major roadblocks actually an
adoption of this practice
should be i missed your voice in between
so you uh
if i could understand correctly you want
to understand what are the challenges of
an insurance company
exactly exactly so exactly i want to
know initially after 2010
uh what are the major roadblocks
constraints and
uh major challenges that has been uh
faced by the
insurance companies when they like
adopted this digital move okay
so as i said uh briefly mentioned in my
slide
that uh you know insurance companies are
basically
you know risk undertakers right they
under they underwrite risk
be the life insurance company they
underwrite life risk if it's a general
insurance company they underwrite
uh general risk involved for the product
if it's a motor insurance
so what is the risk motor car will have
so they will underwrite that they will
price the product accordingly they will
write that
so they are not technology companies
right they are not technology companies
they are
typical traditional financial service
company or insurance companies
now when uh this insurance company uh no
there was a talk
in late uh 200 i mean
2008 2009 in the boardroom where every
ceo would be told that we have to go
digital
digitization
every customer how to make it digital
so what they knew was we need to have a
website
we need to have our products now while
you have your products online
uh their mindset was of how a risk
underwriter would you know work okay i
want
all these complete details from the
customer so if
in life insurance there i remember there
are around 200 uh
you know details we used to take from a
customer to
fill up eight pager form
in life insurance now if
when this digitization started taking
place they have replicated the same form
in the digital mode so there is no
customer experience there is no user
experience
there is no
[Music]
no seamlessness in the journey right
customer wants now if you go to flipkart
you
buy in few clicks you select your
category of product you want to buy
mobile
if you have fascinated with a certain
brand you type the brand
or the model you click you see the
features you see the price you see
warranty you see some reviews and you
click
buy do the payment and
your delivery is done in next two days
or three days or depending on the
product right
insurance company they they don't
understand was taking place
they didn't understand all these things
what they knew is i need to have my
product
but my product will have the same
features which was there in a
physical form you know i'll have 200 uh
you know details
point details i have to take from the
customers so it
took around four or five years for the
insurance company the
initial insurance company who took a
plunge in the digital
to understand how it works so they took
a leap out of
you know e-commerce industry in terms of
creating seamless customer journals
now today if you want to buy a motor
insurance product in any of the
insurance companies ported
or in any of the companies and insurance
portal
comparison could be bank bazaar or a
policy bazaar or easy policy where you
can compare various policies they are
distributed
but you can buy now you will see
that uh you know the the
process is very simple now for motor
insurance just
you know four or five details you give
you know what's the premium of your car
you pay you
come out you put uh your mobile number
and your email address is the basic
to unders to reach out to you the
additional detail which you provide is
your car registration number car make
model
these are the basically two details they
ask the registration number will
define from which city or which
territory your car belongs to basis
which there is a pricing
uh so they will ask that and they will
ask the make model so whether it's a
maruti
make and what is the model for example
model is suzuki swift
of this wave so basis that their pricing
is there
so it is so simple now earlier they used
to ask
lot of details if you look at life
insurance
as i said today you can buy life
in just three or four clicks
you know in one click you have to in
each click you have to put in
three or four details total around 12 to
20 details at the max
and you are done and you you buy the
insurance
so learning the challenges was to bring
in that
seamlessness number one bringing that
experience to the customer
because the customers who are coming
online and buying life insurance are all
millionaires
or buying online or millennials they are
used to
experience right they they
they spend time in uh myntra they spend
time in nikah they spend time in
you know make my trip they spend time in
amazon flipkart so you have to give
that sort of an experience in terms of
buying so that was the initial challenge
second the uh the ceos understood that
uh you know mayor digitization or lip
service won't work we need to understand
that you can take it just as a cost you
have to understand that
this is a huge cost the initial so they
started taking it
as a capital expenditure rather than
opex so they started taking it as a
capex
so they understood the importance of
digitalization hence they started
investing there
so one of my previous companies last
year the ceo
announced they will spend 200 crores
on in next two years to improve
their digital services so you can
imagine how ceos are thinking now
they want to compete with amazons of the
world and when you are tying up with the
amazons and flipkarts of the world you
would also need to have your system
as robust as a tech company those are
tech companies but
we are insurance companies now insurance
companies
now are evolving to become tech
companies or insure tech companies
now uh there are other in short
companies coming up right digit and echo
though they are no you know insurance
companies but they project themselves
as a insure tech companies or a
technology companies now
if you are competing with new age
insurance companies or
new age insure tech distributors like
coffee insurance or bajaj pinser
or say policy buzzers of the world now
you have
also have to overall your technological
system at the back end so that
you can compete the best of the world uh
who offers customers
with the best of technology so those are
the challenges which
no initially we faced
i hope i am able to answer your
questions yeah actually very elaborate a
very descriptive one thanks thanks much
so there are a few students as well who
are pretty uh
enthusiastic to ask you uh questions to
you uh
do we have uh here
are you there afternoon
afternoon sir hey afternoon sir
i had this question that what will the
industry look like in
next 10 years in the same field of this
for the marketing in the eco copper
speed
you are talking about the market size in
next winter next 10 years 20 years this
is what you're asking
i cannot see the future right but what i
can see is uh
basis the present trend in the insurance
industry and what will
the insurance industry market size will
be
in next couple of years so there has
been studies done by
uh you know big uh consultancy firms so
this is one of the consultancy firms
uh big four concern one of the big four
consultancy firms
study they said that by 2030
insurance comp industry in india should
be more than 400 billion dollars
this is the market size they are
projecting now this includes
everything which includes life insurance
general insurance and reinsurance put
together
reinsurance is something which we don't
discuss much
it's a risk which insurance companies
sell
to other uh reinsurance companies so
if i underwrite a risk of a particular
person
so of certain amount that risk i don't
keep it with myself i
sell that risk to other reinsurance
companies
so that is called reinsurance so
reinsurance is also part of insurance
market only
so if you look uh you know insurance
plus reinsurance market
the study they said uh that through the
study they
they assume that we should reach 400
billion dollars
it's which is presently at roughly
around 180 billion or
200 which will do to double
from what it is to it this is in terms
of market size
now in terms of distribution what i see
from my experience of last uh 17 years
in
insurance is uh there will be a
lot of partnerships going around in the
ecosystem
for example you can buy insurance you
don't have to go to
insurance companies website you can buy
a policy bazaar which is a
online distributor right but their
insurance distributor but
other than insurance distribution or
insurance distributor you can buy
insurance in
any where you spend time
for example if you spend time uh playing
games uh you can buy insurance there
or if you spend a lot of time in amazon
or flipkart
or you know you know practo
you can buy insurance there so i see a
lot of partnerships taking place a lot
of
so as of now it's very nascent uh
insurance company as you know is very
regulated they cannot
create very innovative and
technologically high-end product
quickly because they read permission
from the regulator
and regulator is understanding uh how
the technology is getting evolved so
they are also
changing their stance so they are also
bringing in regulations so that
insurance company can become more
innovative in the product design
in the product customization for example
if i want to tie up with
flipkart clickfunnels says i want this
sort of product but as an insurance i
cannot
design that product by if i uh because i
have to go to irda file for that product
so there is a
process which takes a lot of time so ird
has
come up with the sandbox model uh you
know a couple of years back one and a
half years back
but in insurance companies can you know
ideate on a
new uh innovative product and if they
see some success they can file the
product and
they can give permission this is what
the sandbox regulation says so
this is one of the ways from the
regulator to bring in innovation i see a
lot of innovative products coming in
what you see presently the solutions and
offerings from the insurance company
it will completely change in next five
to ten years
for example motor insurance today last
you know last one year i hardly drove my
car right
i have paid insurance for my uh for
entire year
so technically my insurance company made
money out of me
i didn't venture out because of lockdown
i didn't go to office because of
lockdown so this means my car was
you know parked in my carriage which
means
zero is for an insurance company but i
paid
uh you know the premium as per the risk
calculated
uh of the last uh couple of years
trend of the market right so
uh the new regulation or the new
discussion which is taking place in
insurance industry is
a pay as per use so you pay your premium
as per use
if i don't use i don't pay if i if i use
ip
uh so there is a new thing which is
taking place uh
you know development taking place in the
u.s now especially by tesla which
might uh there is a no apprehension that
uh motor insurers globally will be out
of business if tesla
comes into play uh tesla says that they
will sell insurance they will
they will they will not only sell
insurance they will have their own
insurance company to sell into motor
insurance
so this will be the beginning for
automobile
companies selling insurance rather than
automobile companies depending on
insurance company to sell motor
insurance
now tesla is saying that i have you know
you know drivers behavior i know how
what is the risk what is the behavior of
the driver
you know i know how much it travels i
have complete data of the customer so i
can
uh you know underwrite a risk better and
i can price the product better if
this is if this becomes true then
general insurance companies selling
motor insurance will be out of business
in next couple of years
so technology or the evol evolution of
technology will change the complete
dynamics of insurance
product management as well as
distribution management this is what i
understand
i hope i am able to answer your question
okay so
it was pretty clear to me thank you so
much for the
do answer have more questions
yes ma'am
good afternoon sir and good afternoon
thank you for enlightening us with
your experience my question is what are
the biggest challenges facing the
insurance industry
okay uh so insurance industry uh
is very big now if we look at insurance
industry
so there are three broad categories
there
one is life insurance industry other is
non-life insurance in non-life insurance
there is a general insurance industry
which primarily focuses on motor travel
and health
as well as household uh items or
commercial
insurance plus we have specifically
health insurance companies which are
called as standalone healthy
jobs so if you look at life insurance
the challenges life insurers face is
uh over the years life insurance has
been sold
as a tax saving device right this is how
we have
seen life insurance being sold in the in
india now private insurers when they
started uh
you know coming in post 2000 they
started selling life insurance as
not as a not only as a tax saving device
they also started selling it as an
investment uh you know
device or investment products right so
because uh they start they
was focused on eulip which was market
link wherein
uh you know return should be uh the
function of how our stock market works
uh if the stock market goes up your
return goes up and vice versa right
so it started uh
sold in that way now after the turmoil
global terminal financial tamil in 2009
2010 and a lot of issues regarding miss
selling around insurance so life
insurance industry has completely
changed
uh after that so post 2010 they focused
most on traditional plans which
lic or the national insurer is to sell
so they started focusing on
that plus they also tightened that
distribution around the
bank assurance and the broker channels
where
this selling is to happen so missiling
was our
biggest problem in life insurance
industry
in late 2000s so
how they solved was they completely
overrolled the product mix
in the distribution number one and
number two they started focusing more on
templar
in term plan there cannot be any
missiling it's like
this is the premium at your age for this
particular term
this is the premium there is nothing uh
to hide
nothing can be uh missiled there right
only thing which the customer would ask
is what is my premium and what is my
frequency
so you see that's uh you know the
product
mix has changed and the distribution mix
is changed
yeah i hope i am able to answer your
question yes sir thank you so much
uh do we have more questions oh yes
ma'am good afternoon
hey good afternoon sir in your ppt
i would like to ask one thing uh in your
ppt there is one
uh point in opportunity uh focus on no
friends insurance product without any
external influence so what does this
mean
okay so if you look at millennials
millennials don't
want any external influence means
somebody telling
some agents or some brokers telling him
sir this is the product this is the
feature of the product
and you should buy this this is good for
you
they don't want to listen to all these
things they are smart people
they want to know by themselves they
will compare
it with other insurance companies
product
if they find it good they will buy they
want simple
online solutions they don't want to they
don't want any
external influence they don't want a
call for the call center explaining the
product or they don't want
a call from an agent to explain the
product who's trying to sell the product
they don't want that
for example if you want to buy a
cosmetic do you want a guidance from
uh from somebody get this is the
lipstick you need to buy or this is the
mascara you need to buy you don't need
do that right you know
this is what i want you go to naika you
go to
amazon or myndra you select cosmetic as
a segment
you select the product which you want
you select the color
and you see what is the product review
if you want to compare
if you are you know selecting a
particular brand you want to compare
with other brands you compare it there
because then option of comparing it
if you find it okay you buy you don't
get you know uh
you know you don't want external
influence you should buy this this color
is
in or no you know some i bought this
color why don't you buy this you don't
want that you want
a simple uh thing which is
available at your disposal which is
simple to buy
simple to compare and easy and where you
can the payment
payment process is simple so this is
what it means
that youngsters these days doesn't want
any influence by
a banker to sell insurance or an agent
to sell insurance to him
he or she will come directly to an
website compare
and buy by himself or herself this is
what it means
and they don't want any complicated
product they don't buy
term insurance they don't buy you know
uh endowment insurance they don't buy
you
pinch and they they know the simple
thing is insurance in life insurance is
to buy a term product
wherein after death the nominee uh
or the beneficiary will get the required
amount
this is what he wants and he buys that
i hope i am able to answer your question
now yes so yes thank you so
uh so my question is any trend which is
emerging and can sustain
any trend so digital is a trend which is
uh
which is there in insurance industry in
terms of distribution and this is this
is going to sustain now
uh you know min aliens is there i know
in couple of
uh years sinilians will be in the
mainstream in the working
uh stream so those people who
are you know who have grown up uh
using mobiles and buying uh doing
or buying everything online these days
classes are going online so imagine as a
10 year old
student who studies in class c or class
doing at online class what that person
will behave
when that person is 20 25 years old
start starts earning and want to buy
something
everything he or she will buy online so
digital
uh you know is going to stay
digital distribution in digital
distribution there
uh which will sustain in long term is
simple channel specific
products i'll tell you what does it mean
for example if you are a home
loan buyer or if you have bought a house
with a home loan
now you want to cover that risk right if
something happens to you
what will happen to your immediate
family member right because your house
is unknown
so technically bank will take the house
back
if the loan is not uh paid right so what
you do is you buy a
uh you know mortgage term insurance
right modulate
link term insurance which is called as
mrta products or
these days these are called as credit
life products so these are technically
modules reducing term insurance product
sold by life insurance and similar
products are also sold by general
insurance company in a different model
they call it uh you know group term
sorry uh
group uh personal accident policies so
right
now the objective of both the products
are same
in case of any anything that happens to
you in terms of eventuality the
uh you know the money goes to the uh
you know the banks who have financed the
homework
now this product these products these
days uh these products are
designed as per the suitability of an
insurance company
uh these are not customer centric right
so
going forward it will be more customer
centric product
that means if somebody has got a better
credit rating
better credit score uh his or her
premiums would be less uh it will be
more
uh sweeter you know
customized to his or her needs for
example if i
uh lose a job because of a pandemic or
if i lose a job because of
certain reasons will will this also
cover
loss of loss of job will also get
covered so these
are few of the features which might
which is there presently but this is not
there uh you know in a customized way
it's there in a broad general term so
in future i see more of customization
taking place
you know in terms of product offerings
to customers
i hope i am able to answer your
questions often yes sir
any other question yes
[Music]
so yeah thank you sir i said i want to
know after working for
two to three years uh can i switch to
general insurance
okay couple i'll tell you my career
graph so that you will understand better
so i started uh from campus i got
through video con industries so i worked
there for two years
in 2002 i passed out so 2002 to 2004 i
worked in videocon industry selling tv
region washing machine
in a typical fmcd distribution model
suppose that i know
insurance industry at the time was
nascent and they were hiring people
uh their distribution they're augmenting
the distribution i joined builders and
life insurance
in 2004 in agency distribution
so i was uh at the time my hometown is
guava assam which is in assam
so there i joined uh you know
after that i worked there for a year in
the agency distribution then i got an
opportunity icj potential life insurance
why i spent 11 years
i joined and i started a bank assurance
distribution based out of northeast
i grew up in icici from
you know area manager i grew up to zone
that managing the entire east
distribution for
uh frankenstein's then internally i
i took a you know internal job posting
transfer
to bombay in e-commerce so in 2013
i came to e-commerce team in bombay
where i started learning about you know
website
how the technology works how a website
works
what is that science technology
technique behind
the website our website run how to
make uh you know customer buy your
products online how do you manage the
call center
how do we manage the drop leads all
these things so i've learned that
in ics production and after that i
shifted since i shifted to digital so
after you are there
once you are there in digital and you
know digital then
in digital capacity you can shift to any
industry you can super general insurance
you can shift to broking
today i am in general insurance company
in icsa
lombard but before that i was a tata aig
managing
the you know digital distribution and
partnerships
so that was my first stint in general
insurance
presently in icc lombard again in
general insurance but in a different
category altogether in a sme product or
a
commercial line of product where i
manage a website which is
india's first platform for
commercial products so today you know
you find lot of companies selling
insurance online but they are not
commercial products they are all retail
products which caters to you and me
but there is no insurance company
selling commercial line of products
which caters to
a business which captures to a
businessman where he can buy
online es2 he is dependent on uh
you know brokers or legends so that's
what i manage these days
so depends on how you create your niche
you have to create your niche in a
particular category if you are into bank
accounts distribution
so may i know uh which distribution
channel you are in in icsa potential
not a sign yet sir i have to join next
month
yes so you will be based out of jaipur
or will you face out of delhi
sir rajasthan they will be based
so you will be placed in hanuman garden
state no sir
location okay if they have placed you
if they are placing you in ahmedabad
that will be in a traditional
distribution channel
so learn the basics of distribution
there try to keep an
eyes and ears open in digital
distribution see
internally in your website you will be
able to see
opportunities of internal job job
posting the regular the
the you know hr you know rule says that
you have to
be in a position for more than two years
to apply for a
internal job posting in a different
department so if you see
an opportunity or if you are keen uh in
uh you know working in digital or
product management
or in digital marketing if you see an
opportunity in internal job posting
apply for that and try to shift
take care and provide it you know you
learned the
distribution model well and you have
certain idea about digital then
you can easily shift to general
insurance option okay
thank you sir but icsa potential is
another great company to work with i
spent 11 years
starting 11 years of my of my career
there
okay
thank you so much okay all the best
thank you sir there is uh one more
participant
in the meeting i guess who wants to he
is my senior he is my senior yeah he is
my senior so sorry
he has texted in the chat box so first i
think i should invite him for the
question mr alan
hey hey sam hey hi sir
i have a couple of questions with you
and uh this is adding to dr serbi's
question
you did speak about how insurance
companies should guard against
i want to understand and you also spoke
about how individuals who want to make a
career
in the industry should guard again so if
you could give us a
uh example probably what an individual
who started his career
in the insurance initiative guard
against that is my first question
second question is you also spoke very
highly about
uh you know partnerships and strategic
alliances
you can you please tell us what
percentage of your business
does a partnership with strategic land
just contribute
and the last question is that uh if you
could give a
specific example i understand that
you've just joined uh you know icsc
icsc and you're heading the sme business
can you give an example of
the resilience or the issues that you
faced and
what resilience that you you on a
continuous basis took
to kind of turn around an adverse
situation to your benefit
which is a live example of what you did
which was not something you were lacking
but you turned around
to your benefit okay to answer your
first question uh
if i'm if i've understood it correctly
you wanted to know
uh you know uh what is uh
it takes uh for a person to
sustain insurance industry this is what
you meant right in your first question
exactly yeah i agree okay so and to
answer that uh i guess uh
this is a very pertinent question
especially for uh
youngsters who are uh listening and
wants to make a career in insurance
see as i said uh each industry is
challenging right and each industry is
dynamic so when i was in the campus
uh during our times uh i guess
the coveted uh placement would be in a
in an fmcg company be it pdelight or be
hll or png or cadbury or nestle
so those are considered you know big
distribution companies
or companies who had a huge fan
following
you know among the students to make a
career out of that in distribution
i i also had the same uh same thing
right so i joined uh i got an i didn't
get an opportunity in fmcg
i got in uh in the consumer durables it
was video one
videocon was a falling brand at the time
it was a
you know number one brand in 90s
and video one actually taught indians
how to
wash clothes in washing machine so
coming from a brand of that repute uh
you know i learned a lot about
distribution in ensure
of fmcg but distribution in insurance
is very challenging here everything
depends on
how you perform it's exactly like
a cricket match now in a cricket match
it's a pressure
on a either you are a batsman or a
baller it's
always on you to if you're a baller to
contain runs and take wickets and if
you're a batsman
to skip scoring at a brisk pace
so it's your individual skill
and the resilience you have and the
perseverance you
you take to achieve or drive
organizational objectives so two things
which is very important
is you have certain
level of skills right because of which
you get selected in the organization
now focus on your skill
so that others you become so good in
your
skill that others find it hard to
compete with you
for example what i did specifically was
i found my nation bank assurance
i worked first year in agency
distribution agency distribution
i i enjoyed a job but i found my niche
in bank assurance and
hence i stayed for 11 years in ica
potential and i made a name
for myself in bankruptcy because bank
assurance i understood
the basics of the distribution where you
need to
you know develop relationship with the
people whom we are dealing with
i'm dealing with bank people uh the
front line officers to the branch
managers to the zonal managers to the
area managers
i need to you know bring in uh you know
a relationship management skill to four
for which i did my best to develop
that repo with everybody at every level
and i
told my team to develop repo with
everybody
now if you develop that repo and build
relationship
people will buy your product it's
exactly like
how a doctor prescribes a medicine after
a medical representative of a particular
pharmaceutical company
visits him it depends on the
relationship skill of that person
influencing the doctor to write more
prescription similarly
the bank has got an option of selling
you know right now bank has got option
of selling three insurance companies
during my time it was one insurance
company but other was general insurance
company i used to compete with general
insurance company and mutual fund
because i was selling you know eulips
through banks
and i used to tell banks that how ulip
is better
than a mutual fund or how youtube is
better than
uh or how my other you know traditional
products are better than
i know other uh you know mrta products
which uh general insurance companies are
selling in the bank
so that sort of skills uh
you know basics you need to understand
and you need to hold on to that
as as well as you need to add new skills
for example learning few tricks of
digital
learning few tricks of i know analytics
these days analytics plays a major role
to influence decision if you are good at
analytics and if you can
study data well and present the data in
uh in a in a way which
uh bring in lot of insights
those are the skills which you need to
develop and those are the
skill which will help you in in your
you know you know in your tough times
those are the things which you need to
have to succeed in insurance
uh i hope i am able to answer your first
question uh sir
yeah definitely one question last is
that what
you spoke highly about uh you know
partnership with legal alliances
so currently what percentage part what
percentage of your business is coming
through this third party
okay partnerships okay uh so now
question is uh how do you define
your digital distribution now digital
distribution for an insurance company
are threefold
one is the basic business with a website
that means how many business
uh conversion i'm getting straight
through my website that means customer
coming to my website
without any external intervention
external intervention here is the
intervention from the call center
without any intervention on the call
center he is
or she is buying the product on his uh
on his or
her own getting the doing the payment
and issuing the policy
by uh by the by himself or herself
so this is one second is the
contribution through the call
centerpiece
call centerpiece would be you know any
drop customers any customers dropping
from your website you get that lead
you call up the customer try to sell the
you know sell it
uh sell the customer online uh by
pushing or nudging him to the call
center this is the second aspect of
digital distribution the third aspect of
digital distribution is
tying up with new age
irda licensed distributors like web
aggregators or brokers like brokers like
cover fox
or uh web agriculture like policy bazaar
or say easy policy
so they are financial service companies
they are part of insurance they are
licensed by iit
so this is the third segment through
which you get digital business
and the fourth segment through which you
get digital business is the partnership
business
which is the strategic alliances
business so this
segment is very very new this segment is
very very
nascent uh from if you ask me from
only from the strategic alliances piece
how uh
how much business it will contribute it
it will be contribute not more than
one or less than one percent of overall
business of a company
because this is an evolving industry and
right now what the product solution
which i am offering to
a ecosystem player is my traditional
products which i have
right now they want a very uh
you know customized simple
size insurance product for which
insurance companies are working with the
regulator regulator is understanding the
importance of
bringing regulations to bring in lot of
innovation in product management
and you will see as innovation comes in
the distribution through the ecosystem
will increase and the contribution to
the
uh you know business from the ecosystem
or
the digital alliances or strategic
alliances will increase
from present less than one percent or
one percent two it might go to
twenty twenty five percent in next five
years
this is what my understanding about the
digital distribution
and moreover i know policy buzzer is
growing day by day if you look at the
digital distribution
of insurance company in india
and five years back it was just around
600 crore market
today it is around 2000 crore market
digital distribution
uh you know wherein you sell through
your website you sell through policy
bazaars of the world you sell through
other
digital distributors so this market
five years back there were only 600
crores both life insurance and general
insurance put together
now general insurance would be around
1200 3900
tolerance around six seven eight hundred
will be life insurance industry total
two thousand crore could be the digital
distribution
so this is going to increase many photos
on a lighter note tell me one thing
policy check currently will you kill me
following up with the calls
does that add to your business uh sir
one thing
which we have been taught in b school is
to become aggressive
as a salesperson we have to be
aggressive
not to let any opportunity miss so
any distributor if they get a lead
they will try to you know
follow up the customer till the customer
doesn't buy so that's how a normal sales
cycle works right
and the customer doesn't buy or shuts
your phone
so there's ways you can tell that i was
just checking please delete my number
please don't call i don't think they
will bother you
because even i have you know given my
number in policy bazaar
if they follow me uh follows up with me
for a particular product i say that i
was just chatting
i am from an insurance company don't
bother me they don't bother
so we can we have all the rights to
bother you uh
sir again uh tri guidelines clearly says
that when you are
when you make a voluntary disclosure to
be
called because all insurance companies
and all those distribution companies you
are talking about they take a voluntary
disclosure from you
that our since you have come to my
website to check
certain things uh our representative
will
call back and this will override your
dnd so
you voluntarily
or explicitly say that you should be
called hence they get give you
okay thank you so much sam
yeah any other questions so i
i found in chat box our director mim
dr jesse ram has mentioned a very good
question so mom would you like to
proceed
yeah very good evening summers hey good
evening ma'am
one question which i wanted to ask it is
very much related to the present
pandemic situation
was there any under right laws that the
industry might have faced because of the
pandemic
and how you people have dealt with the
same
it's a very good question ma'am coming
from somebody who understand insurance
and the risk management so health
insurance industry
is really under tremendous loss health
especially
standalone health insurance companies
for
general insurance companies like us we
can
you know negate that loss from health
business through
better business from other segments so
health standalone health insurance
companies are in red
those who have written products which is
uh
no if you look at health insurance so
now
the more older your policy is
it's more risk you you take because till
first four years there are a lot of
exclusions
right now for example pre-existing
diseases doesn't cover in
first four years or say certain
maternity is not covered in past four
years
or certain uh you know clauses you know
are there which doesn't cover in first
four years
so moment of policy health insurance
policy is
more than four years old the risk
from the risk perspective the health
insurance takes more risk
so any health insurance companies who
are
you know you know more than five years
old in terms of their customer book
they are facing major problem
so uh they actually are uh
running under huge losses because of uh
because the pandemic has brought in huge
claims
investment one other question which i
wanted to ask when you talk about
investment we always talk about
creating a portfolio so can we think
about creating a portfolio for a
customer in the
insurance industry as well can we think
in that line and then
so remember rightly mentioned what i
understand
is uh creating a insurance uh portfolio
right live health general
you know for a customer for a customer
now
insurance is a products category you
know
insurance penetration is hardly five or
six percent
if you look at individual basis but if
you look at the government uh
initiatives of uh you know what
government has taken
since last six seven years so these are
all part of group
group group insurance so if you include
that
then the penetration might be around
50 to 20 but those are not real
penetration because
customer doesn't know that he has or she
has got insurance
and now i don't know whether you are
aware or not
there is also an insurance against your
pf account from two lakhs to seven lakhs
hardly anybody knows even uh educated
person even
i am sure some of my friends from
insurance industry doesn't know that
they've got insurance
okay so ma'am so people are not aware of
insurance
the problem is that now we are talking
about creating a
portfolio now there is a company which
is called bhima pay which is a new intro
tech company it's a
distribution company they are trying to
create the same thing
which you are mentioning what they are
trying to say is create
a fema pay account with them and you
will career will create
a insurance portfolio for you we'll
simplify because
insurance is an agreement right it's a
legal agreement between an insurer
and the customer and uh and it's a very
uh technical uh technical
technical thing and there are a lot of
jargons people don't understand half of
the jargons yes ninety percent of the
jobs
next question so people ninety percent
of the people don't understand jargon
even i from an insurance industry even
today
after spending so much of years in
insurance i don't know hundred percent
of the insurance jobs
because it's changing i'm learning i'm
also learning
so no body in insurance industry would
be able to
vouch that he or she knows hundred
percent about insurance because in the
insurance is
such a vast vast topic if somebody knows
all about distribution
might not know much about underwriting
much about uh
you know actuarial calculation so there
are a lot
lot of things come into play
doesn't know more about claims so i i
can be
good at distribution knowing the product
management and
distribution but i might not be good at
risk management actuarials
or say claims claims management is also
one of the important aspect of insurance
business so so i am from the front and
side of the distribution
of the insurance distribution so
insurance if you look at
uh you know people don't understand lot
of jargons
so i'm i'm sure it will take at least a
couple of years
for people to understand insurance
moment it comes into a normal lexicon
that insurance is an important thing is
a part of our life then only you will be
see that people will start creating a
bouquet
for themselves or you know a book for
themselves
for insurance life insurance you know
term insurance health insurance
now people are buying a lot of health
insurance now pandemic
has led to huge business for like the
health insurance company also
their businesses are increasing you know
small insurance company health insurance
company
is to do 5 600 crores a year they are
reaching 1000 crores
so this pandemic is imp is uh
though it causing a lot of pain in terms
of claims but
at the same time it is also helping uh
health insurance companies to
garner a lot of premium from the market
i hope i am able to answer your question
the last question from my side is
uh have you ever observed that these
customers across
the from baby boomers to generation z
is there any fluctuation happening with
respect to the product cycle that they
are
looking forward to and the product
preferences or is it
still the same and is ird customizing
itself
according to the changing need even
though
ma'am what i understood from your
question is
how products are getting influenced
in uh in terms of uh
certain segments of population coming
into play and buying insurance for
example
uh millennials to baby bloomers and
zinilians this is what you are trying to
say man
okay so as of now there is no change
only change which we have seen i have
seen in life insurance industry is
people focusing on pure term insurance
this is hence since last five six years
you'll see
term insurance every company is
launching various
uh you know variety of the time
insurance
term insurance with lot of features now
in initially term insurance
used to be very very simple vanilla
product without
much of fun fare these days you see term
insurance comes with lot of features
so what has influenced a company's
decision to bring in lot of feature
is because uh term insurance uh
distribution uh or demand is getting uh
you know generated through you know
millennials and millions want
something more in that plane term
insurance hence
this is the present trend which i see in
term insurance
going forward what i see is a
new sort of insurance coming into play
which will be very session side product
uh you know small ticket size product
for example i sold a product in my
previous uh
you know uh you know uh in my previous
company was uh
selling cycle insurance this was india's
first
cycle insurance i sold now in front end
it was uh you know uh if you're if you
buy a bicycle
these days people buy bicycle not
because it's a mode of transportation
but it's a
uh because of health reasons right a lot
of you see a lot of
urban people using cycles and cycle
sales has started increasing now there
was a decline in rd 2000
uh post 2012 uh i know i met mr pankaj
munjal who is the owner
with the chairman of euro cycles he says
that market has increased post 2000
2012. and since 2015 is saying
yeah we have launched various types of
cycles now they have launched electric
cycles also
so those validities are also coming so
cycle market is
increasing so hero being the market
leader i tried
we tied up with them we sold cycle
insurance at the back end
there is no innovation it was simple
personal all risk
if somebody from insurance you
understand it's a plane cover
anything at your house will be covered
which is called personal
altruist if you buy this product so if
you have got any jewelry
any electronic items at your home it
covers again
fire burglary and theft it covers
against these three risks
so i covered cycle under that risk
that if your cycle gets stolen my
front-end pitch was
cycle gets stolen or it gets accidental
damage
if it's an accidental damage i will pay
for the damage which is again like water
insurance
and if it's if it's a loss because of
theft
or burglary then i will pay you the
price of the cycle which is again like
motor insurance
right so i took a leaf out of motor
insurance and i
made personnel all risk to be sold as
cycle insurance
so innovation if you look at mam so
there was innovation at the front end
but the back end it was basic insurance
product
so if you ask me samrat do you have
something called actual cycle insurance
filed with ird i don't have so paddle
cycle insurance was there in early 70s
and 80s
sold by you know generous public general
insurance but they never focused so this
product is
still there with them but they never
sell so now after
my experiment with hero cycles in my
previous team
now a lot of companies are coming up
with the new varieties of cycle
insurance
you will see backpack insurance i sold
backpack insurance i tied up with
the wildcraft selling backpack insurance
that means
your backpack gets stolen it's covered
no question asked what about the price
of the backpack i will pay you
so those are the innovation which i am
bringing in terms of strategic alliances
what arshoe sir was asking
and so sincerely was asking is how much
business
will will contribute from the strategic
alliances it's still nascent it's
but in future you will see a lot of
cesare products coming in will take uh
the market by storm
i hope i'm able to answer your question
ma'am yeah yeah yeah thank you thanks a
lot
i hope there are no more questions as of
now
um hi um one more last thing i i know we
have taken lots and lots
of your time i guess so it's just one
and a half hours it's two hours two
two and three hours you said we have
time till uh till that time right
so i i mean i always have a view of this
and uh
probably the students might also you
know would uh
in their heart acknowledge the same that
insurance is considered to be a
necessary evil
right and usually the students are not
willing to go for
this sector as in choosing for their
placements and all that stuff
they actually somehow would as you were
mentioning you
also had uh you know pid light into your
list and something all these brands
so i understand and i mean that is the
scene that is the scenario that we face
usually but what a piece of advice that
you'd like to give that
this sector is is good and what is your
view on this
i mean i understand that you have been
on the helm of affairs in this sector
certainly uh but what drove you here
what motivated you here and what a piece
of advice that you'd like to
share to the students who actually are
not actually willing to go for
but are somewhere going that kind of
stuff
okay a very important question you have
asked and
i spent my time at the most of
the difficult times in insurance uh
during 2009 to 2011 where insurance
industry were
duped
because of people making money because
by doing
you know things which are not ethically
right
i have seen uh you know people you know
appreciating me
uh that i am working insurance but after
some years people started avoiding me
because i work in insurance so people i
have seen people
not i won't say ostracizing it will be a
very tough word
but i've seen people avoiding me in
society
moment they came to know i am from
insurance and they used to look down
upon
well if you look at if i use
typical hindi words which they uses
so these are the terms which i have
listened uh you know
uh from various folks uh you know in
society and in my place
but insurance now has changed no
insurance company
so it was a fault of insurance company
also because of
doing numbers numbers numbers if you
pressurize people people will find out
ways
to do that numbers hence you know you
see
miss selling if you look at cricket
these days because of
fast scoring pattern which has come
today in t20 the cricket dynamics
batsman dynamics has changed
what not shorts you see today so this is
what has happened in insurance also
because of achieving those numbers now
insurance company have realized
that you know distribution has to
be in such a way so that people doesn't
feel cheated
so people used to feel cheated in buying
insurance life especially life insurance
general insurance again it's a
need-based product so and moreover it is
uh
it is a it is uh mandated by law
so if you have a motor car you have to
buy a motor insurance because it is
mandated by law under motor motor
vehicle act of 1988
life insurance is not mandated so life
insurance especially in life insurance
people used to
feel cheated when someone sold insurance
so that thing has completely changed
post 2013
now insurance company focused on term
insurance and
started focusing selling it on their
website
so moment you start selling on the
website so there is no external
influence
to influence you other than the
economic models which you use uh you
know nudge
theory which you use to nudge a customer
to buy
right that's how you design in your
journey
other than that other than that there is
no external influence
hence you know the adoption
of insurance through digital medium has
improved
plus it has also changed the
overall uh you know negative uh
view of the life insurance industry
because insurance industry started
became more
serious about distributors they started
finalizing distributors
where it was selling complaints game you
know banks uh you know selling insurance
rbi came heavily uh strongly uh on them
so they tightened their distribution
regulation process or the
selling process you know how it didn't
be sold there were
calls going to the customer from the
bank's side or insurance company side
this has been told to you
whether these all these things have been
explained to you or not if it's not
if you're not happy then you can we'll
refund your policy so those are the
proactive steps taken by
insurers now today i don't think
that negative uh connotation
for life insurance industry is there
but i understand that youngsters
are averse to selling insurance because
they find
that you have to be following up with a
customer
so that is something which youngsters
don't like which i have seen
which we as an uh you know i guess lot
of hr has understood this
so we are changing the role of
youngsters from the campuses when we are
hiring so when we are hiring so i hired
uh
from campus this time so most of our
hireds
are for product management and uh
for analytics so i have taken people for
product management
and for analytics and for plane
distribution which is agency
distribution or banker distribution
we don't hire from campus we hire people
who are graduates with
one or two years of experience we are
that category of people who want to
aspire to work in a corporate
so we so so for frontline selling
our hiring is hiring paternalistic
skills so i'm
i think uh the students at irm should
not think negative about insurance
because i
made a carrier out of insurance industry
passed out in 2002 graduated from irm
since 2004 i am in insurance industry
so i am a living example from irm
who has done well in insurance i won't
say i have done very well but i will say
i have done reasonably well
in my career uh but there is a lot to
learn from me
also uh in insurance
i hope i'm able to answer your question
i would love to hear a few more
questions from students if they have any
questions regarding any apprehension
they have about
about the industry because uh that is
more important because
insurance industry i know as surgeon
imam you have rightly put in
uh is has got a lot of negativity around
uh students don't want to join a life
insurance or a general insurance company
uh kapil i guess uh asked one of the
questions who joined
like uh you know icsa potential an ics a
prudential i worked there for 11 years
and i it's a
fantastic organization to work with uh
very you know
employee-friendly organization but at
the same time there will be tremendous
pressure but if you are able to
handle that pressure i am sure kapil
can grow you know uh in uh noisy
potential
and other folks uh or friends of puppy
who are
there listening uh i'm sure uh
this will give you a lot of confidence
now uh first of all one of your
batchmates or one of your friends
getting placed in ici potential
and i talked how i see the potential is
all about as an insurance company
thank you for sharing your experience
with us
and enlightening us with the latest
trends and era
we hope to look upon your work and
achieve success like you in future
now i would request our respected
director fms adam
dr jesse john mum for extending the vote
of thanks
um very good evening to all the students
somewhere dr tarjani and all the faculty
members
it was actually a you can say it is
almost
going to be two hours of taxing and um
he was
uh mr samad was going on speaking even
without a break i appreciate your skills
for that
and then without any weight you are
conversing with the students
and um just it was really an eye-opening
session for the students as well because
one of the cracks which i was able to
make out from this whole conversation is
the passion to grow with the industry
with the sector with the organization
and develop your skillses i think this
is the crux which you have which you
wanted to communicate with the students
and it was well communicated students
that
in respect of the sector with which you
are associated with
it is going to be the skill sets it is
going to be the knowledge that is going
to make you different
that is going to make you a different
person in that particular industry
respect of the industry
and as surgery members saying um icc
prudential came to the campus
and we would like to invite ics a
lombard also to the campus so that
we still have two students left to be
placed so we will be really
happy if you can think of considering
your alma mater for the
placements as well so i'm so sorry for
being a bit selfish but didn't come to
the
placement services i'm a bit selfish in
that particular
situation i'm so sorry for that and um
i'm really um
happy that many of you attended and you
all
asked so many good questions it is it is
actually insurance is the world which
which is yet to be explored because it
has now covered only two percentage of
the whole market
so naturally there is certainly there is
around 95 percentage or 98 percentage
growth you can expect
so it is an industry with which you can
grow with explore
uh various new silos as well develop
your own dish
skill sets so that you will be able to
make your own mark in that particular
sector in your own way
and thanks a lot samar gosh for sparing
your time and
i think we have got another alumni also
ashutosh
we look forward for your session as well
in the future
uh days to come thank you sir thanks a
lot
thank you anything for samara do you
know yeah look forward
sir thank you so much
[Laughter]
it is good it is amazing really it is a
great insightful session i would believe
and we look forward to many of these
happenings so great great work
uh i think everyone at irm
we look forward for most sessions under
the ages of alumni talk series
definitely thank you so much ma'am
definitely thank you have a nice day
thank you bye thank you mam
thank you ma'am thank you rustam sir
special thanks to you for
helping me out with the presentation for
moving the presentation forward
i hope to see you soon when i am there
next time in jaipur will come and visit
the
visit my uh you know college uh
sir whenever i'm
[Music]
he'll pull me to jaipur and i'm sure
and all the best students
thank you thank you so thank you sir
[Music]
thank you sir
foreign